And welcome back.
돌아오신 걸 환영해요
You've just seen GPT four zero spectacularly failed to work on our hard Python conversion problem.
GPT 40이 하드 파이썬 변환 문제를 멋지게 해결하지 못한 걸 보셨는데요
And now we're going to see how Claude handles the same problem.
이제 클로드가 같은 문제를 어떻게 해결하는지 보죠
So we run the optimize method.
최적화 메서드를 실행해요
We get back a bunch of stuff from Claude.
클로드에게서 많은 걸 얻어요 Get up
Here it is.
여기 있네요
And now we will run the clang optimized, uh, the method to compile and optimize this code and run
이제 clang 최적화된 메서드를 실행하겠습니다 컴파일하고 코드를 최적화하는 거죠 실행해
it and see what we get.
어떻게 되는지 보죠
Oh, it was still generating.
계속 발전하고 있었어요
And so a lot happened there.
많은 일이 있었어요
And the reason that there was a long pause is that it hadn't yet finished producing the code, as I
긴 정지가 있었던 이유는 아직 코드 생성을 완료하지 않았기 때문입니다.
just saw that it was like halfway finished, but it did just finish and then it compiled, and then
반 정도 완료된 것을 보았습니다. 하지만 완료하고 컴파일하고
it ran and it got the correct answer.
실행해서 올바른 답을 얻었어요.
And wowzer look at how fast that is.
정말 빠른 것 좀 보세요
Look at the difference.
차이를 보세요
Not only did Claude do this, but Claude has just done shockingly well.
클로드는 이 일뿐만 아니라 놀라울 정도로 잘했어요
That you will notice, is two milliseconds, two milliseconds Compared to the time that the Python code
2밀리초입니다 파이썬 코드에서 파이썬 코드로 다시 이동하는 시간의
have to go up to the Python code again.
2밀리초죠
Uh, and where did we do the Python code?
파이썬 으로 코드는 어디서 했었죠?
Here we go.
시작할게요
The Python code got the same answer in 27 seconds.
파이썬 + 코드는 27초 만에 같은 답을 얻죠
So, uh, I'm going to need to get a calculator here just to quickly, uh, tell myself 27.
get 27 계산기 좀 가져올게요 빨리 27이라고 되뇌어 봐야겠어요
It's something like 13,000 times faster.
13,000배는 빨라요
Wow, wow.
대단해요
So you should be blown away by that.
깜짝 놀라실 거예요
Uh, sometimes GPT four hasn't failed and has managed to generate some code.
GPT 4가 실패하지 않고 코드를 생성할 때도 있어요
And when it does, the code that it's generated, for me at least, um, has been faster, but more
그렇게 되면 생성된 코드는 적어도 제 경우엔 더 빨라져요 하지만 10배나
like, uh, 10 or 100 times faster.
100배 더 빨라지죠
Not like Claude.
클로드 같지 않아요
So how on earth has Claude been able to do this?
클로드는 대체 어떻게 이걸 해냈을까요?
Uh, how has it managed to make such highly optimized code?
어떻게 최적화된 코드를 만들 수 있었을까요?
Like, is there something wrong with Python that, I mean, there must be something very wrong with
파이썬 을 잘못 사용하고 있는 건가요? 파이썬 을 잘못 사용하고 있는 게 분명합니다.
Python if it can be so, so much faster.
아주 아주 빠르게 사용할 수 있다면요.
Well, no, there is a little bit more to the tale.
아뇨, 비트가 좀 더 있어요
Um, if we look at the optimized code that Claude generated.
클로드가 생성한 최적화된 코드를 보세요
Hang on.
잠깐만요
I think I have to close this and double click again to see it.
이걸 닫고 다시 더블 클릭해야 볼 수 있을 것 같아요
Here we go.
시작할게요
Um, there is a bit more to the tale.
비트가 좀 더 있어요
There is a bit more to the tale.
비트가 더 있어요
What has happened?
무슨 일이죠?
What has happened is that, Claude, the direction that we gave Claude was to make sure that the same
클로드에게 방향을 지시했을 때 같은 반응을 최대한
response was generated, identical response in the fastest possible time.
빨리 만들어내라고 했어요
And the prompt was very careful to say re-implement in C plus plus.
프롬프트는 C++에서 다시 구현하라고 조심스럽게 말했죠
And that is exactly what Claude has done.
클로드가 그렇게 했어요
Claude, amazingly, has analyzed the code and understood the intent of the code.
클로드는 놀랍게도 코드를 분석하고 그 의미를 이해했어요
Um, perhaps with a hint by the name of the function.
함수 이름에 힌트를 준 것 같아요
Although don't don't, uh, don't give it all away with the name of the function.
함수 이름만 가지고 다 말씀하시진 마세요
And there's a few things to try and cause it off track, but it has re-implemented this in a completely
궤도에서 벗어나게 한 몇 가지 요소가 있었지만 완전히 다른
different approach, using a theorem that I think it's called Shannon's, uh, algorithm.
방식으로 재설정했어요 섀넌의 알고리즘이라는 정리를 이용해서요
Uh, I think that's right.
그런 것 같아요
Yes, it is called Shannon's algorithm.
네, 섀넌의 알고리즘이에요
Uh, and, uh, it is an approach that allows you to solve this puzzle just with one loop.
이 방법은 이 퍼즐을 한 번의 루프로 풀 수 있게 해줘요
One loop through.
한 바퀴 돌아요
Uh, sorry, I'm on the wrong loop here.
죄송해요, 다른 루프에 있었네요
This is the loop.
이게 루프예요
One loop through, not a nested loop.
한 루프만 통과하면 돼요
Uh, and as a result, uh, you can see there are there are, in fact, uh, two of them side by side.
그 결과, 보시다시피 두 개가 나란히 놓여 있어요
But it's not a, it's not a, uh, a nested loop, a loop within a loop.
하지만 이건 중첩된 루프가 아니라 루프 안의 루프예요
Um, and that allows you to get to the answer in a fraction of the time.
아주 짧은 시간 안에 get get에 도달할 수 있죠
So what Claude has done, which is so ingenious, is it's understood the intent of the function, it's
클로드가 한 것은 정말 기발합니다 함수의 의도를 이해했어요
not just translated something from Python to the equivalent C plus plus code, it has reimplemented
파이썬 을 동등한 C++ 코드로 번역한 게 아닙니다 취소했어요
it just as it was prompted to get the same answer in a blazingly, uh, fast amount of time.
같은 답을 얻도록 프롬프트된 거죠 아주 짧은 시간 동안에요
So I would say that is a terrific, terrific result by Claude.
클로드가 정말 멋진 결과를 냈네요
Uh, and, uh, a round of applause there.
박수 한번 주세요
And it's certainly consistent with what we've seen from the Seal leaderboard.
씰 리더보드에서 본 것과 일치해요
Claude 3.5 sonnet, uh, rules the show.
클로드 3세예요 5개의 소네트가 쇼를 지배하죠
Uh, Claude for the win.
클로드가 이겼어요